### Cristian Gómez Portes

Calle Ermita, nº4, bajo C Horcajo de los Montes, Ciudad Real, 13110 Cristian.Gomez2@alu.uclm.es

tel1: 638938702 tel2: 926775462

#### Research interests

My research topics cover Visualization of Programs and Algorithms, the use of Augmented Reality techniques and 3D graphics. Besides that, I am interested in subfields related to Artificial Intelligence such as Natural Language Processing and Computer Vision, among others.

### Education

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

University College of Computer Science, Ciudad Real, Spain

July 2018

FDP: Graphical representation generator system for the visualization of programs and algorithms using Mixed-Reality.

## Professional experience

Microsoft HoloLens Developer

July - February, 2017 - 2018

Furious Koalas Interactive S.L, Ciudad Real, Spain

• Developed the process of scanning and mapping the environment to detect tables as main part of the video game. This project was performed to teach children programming using the Windows mixed-reality device, Microsoft HoloLens. My participation of this project was thanks to the *Telefónica Talentum* scholarship.

# Significant projects

**ARmov**: A mixed-reality video game which was developed using *Unity*, a video game engine and *Microsoft HoloLens*, a holographic computer that allows to interact with holograms in the real world. It intends to teach children the basic aspects about programming resolving levels that increase their difficulty towards the progress of the video game.

**AsgAR**: AsgAR is a system developed as a Final Degree Project at University of Castilla La Mancha (UCLM), whose objective is to generate graphical representations based on a metaphor or roads and traffic signs for visualizing programs and algorithms using the *Microsoft HoloLens* device. http://blog.uclm.es/grupochico/proyecto-iapro/.

## Workshops

3D design and modelling

November – January, 2018 – 2019

Public library, Ciudad Real, Spain

• Teaching of the Blender tool covering aspects from modelling, textures, materials and animations to illumination and integration with real image.

## Certifications

- Preliminary English Test, Cambridge Language Assessment, 2016.
- First English Test, Cambridge Language Assessment, 2018.

### Awards

III Call of prizes destinated to Final Degree Projects

December, 2018

• Second prize granted by Caja Rural Catilla La Mancha in the branch of knowledge of Architecture and Engineering to the best Final Degree Projects.

## **Scholarships**

Scholarship from Ministry of Education and Professional Training

2013-2018

• Scholarship granted by Ministry of Education and Professional Training every year during the Bachelor and Master of Science to develop these degrees.